<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Career Counsellor</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="whatisCC">Our Career Counselling App can help students understand the career exploration process and how their skills and interests match up with a chosen career path. Career counseling can help people understand themselves and the world of work to make career, educational, and life decisions. It can also help people who are restive in their current career paths.</string>
    <string name="whyCCisImp">Ch .</string>
    <string name="jobSoftware">Software developers are in high demand across various sectors, including technology companies, financial services, healthcare, e-commerce, and entertainment. The job prospects for software developers are expected to remain favorable, with opportunities for entry-level and experienced developers alike. Additionally, the growth of emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, cloud computing, and the Internet of Things (IoT) is creating new opportunities for software developers to innovate and create cutting-edge solutions.</string>
    <string name="skillsSoftware">Software developers require a combination of technical skills, problem-solving abilities, and communication skills. Technical skills include proficiency in programming languages such as Java, Python, JavaScript, C++, and SQL, as well as familiarity with development frameworks, libraries, and tools. Problem-solving abilities are essential for identifying and solving complex technical challenges, debugging code, and optimizing performance. Communication skills are important for collaborating with team members, understanding client requirements, and presenting technical solutions effectively.

To become a software developer, individuals typically need a bachelors degree in computer science, software engineering, or a related field. While formal education is valuable, practical experience gained through internships, coding projects, and open-source contributions is also highly regarded by employers. Software developers may pursue additional certifications, training, or specialization in specific programming languages, development methodologies, or technology stacks to enhance their skills and marketability in the field.</string>
    <string name="salarySoftware">Software developers salaries vary based on factors such as experience, location, industry, and specialization. According to data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS), the median annual wage for software developers was $110,140 in May 2020. However, salaries can range significantly higher for experienced developers with specialized skills or in-demand expertise. Entry-level salaries for software developers may be lower, particularly for recent graduates or those working in startups or smaller companies, while experienced developers in tech hubs such as Silicon Valley may earn six-figure salaries or more.</string>

    <string name="jobCivil">Civil engineering is a field with steady demand, driven by infrastructure development, urbanization, and environmental concerns. Job prospects for civil engineers are expected to remain favorable, with opportunities in various sectors including construction, transportation, water resources, environmental engineering, and structural engineering. The demand for civil engineers may vary based on geographical location, economic conditions, and government infrastructure projects.</string>
    <string name="skillsCivil">Civil engineers require a diverse set of technical, interpersonal, and problem-solving skills to succeed in their profession. Technical skills include proficiency in structural analysis, design software (such as AutoCAD, Revit, and SAP2000), project management, and construction techniques. Additionally, civil engineers must possess a solid understanding of engineering principles in areas such as mechanics, materials science, geotechnical engineering, and fluid mechanics. Effective communication skills are essential for civil engineers to collaborate with team members, communicate project requirements to clients and stakeholders, and present technical information clearly and concisely. Problem-solving abilities are also crucial, as civil engineers are often tasked with analyzing complex problems, identifying solutions, and making informed decisions.</string>
    <string name="salaryCivil">The salary of civil engineers can vary based on factors such as experience, location, industry, and level of education. According to data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS), the median annual wage for civil engineers was $88,570 in May 2020. Entry-level civil engineers may earn around $60,000 to $70,000 per year, while experienced professionals with advanced degrees and certifications may earn six-figure salaries. Salaries may be higher in metropolitan areas with high costs of living and strong demand for civil engineering services.</string>

    <string name="jobGraphic">Graphic design is a dynamic field with diverse job prospects, requiring a combination of creativity, technical skills, and industry knowledge. Job prospects for graphic designers are influenced by factors such as technological advancements, market demand, and industry trends. In todays digital age, the demand for graphic designers remains strong across various sectors, including advertising, marketing, publishing, web design, and multimedia production. Graphic designers play a crucial role in creating visual communication materials that effectively convey messages, engage audiences, and enhance brand identities. With the rise of digital media and online platforms, there are opportunities for graphic designers to work in areas such as user interface design, interactive media, motion graphics, and digital marketing. Additionally, freelance and remote work opportunities are common in the graphic design industry, allowing designers to work independently or collaborate with clients and agencies on a project basis. Overall, the job prospects for graphic designers are favorable, with opportunities for creative expression, professional growth, and career advancement.</string>
    <string name="skillsGraphic">In terms of skills and qualifications, graphic designers require a blend of technical expertise, design proficiency, and creative flair. Technical skills include proficiency in design software such as Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Sketch, and other industry-standard tools. Design proficiency encompasses principles of typography, color theory, layout composition, and visual hierarchy, enabling graphic designers to create aesthetically pleasing and effective designs. Creative flair involves the ability to generate original ideas, concepts, and visual solutions that meet client objectives and project requirements. Additionally, strong communication skills are essential for graphic designers to collaborate with clients, understand project briefs, and present design concepts effectively. Problem-solving abilities are also important, as graphic designers may encounter challenges in conceptualizing and executing designs that effectively communicate messages and engage audiences. While formal education in graphic design or a related field is beneficial, practical experience, a strong portfolio, and a passion for design are often valued more highly by employers. Continuous learning and staying updated with industry trends and technologies are key for graphic designers to remain competitive in the field.</string>
    <string name="salaryGraphic">In terms of salary, the compensation for graphic designers can vary based on factors such as experience, location, industry, and level of expertise. According to data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS), the median annual wage for graphic designers was $53,380 in May 2020. Entry-level graphic designers may earn around $35,000 to $45,000 per year, while experienced professionals with advanced skills and extensive portfolios may earn six-figure salaries. Freelance graphic designers may charge hourly rates or project-based fees, which can vary widely based on factors such as project complexity, client budget, and market demand. Overall, the salary of graphic designers reflects their skills, experience, and ability to deliver high-quality design work that meets client expectations and achieves project objectives.</string>

    <string name="jobDoctor">Doctors, also known as physicians or medical practitioners, have promising job prospects, extensive skill requirements, and varying salary ranges. Job prospects for doctors are generally excellent, with demand driven by factors such as population growth, aging populations, and advancements in medical technology. Physicians are needed across various medical specialties and practice settings, including hospitals, clinics, private practices, research institutions, and public health organizations. While job prospects vary by specialty and geographical location, overall demand for doctors remains strong, particularly in areas experiencing population growth or underserved healthcare needs.</string>
    <string name="skillsDoctor">In terms of skills and qualifications, doctors undergo extensive education, training, and licensure requirements. Core skills include medical knowledge, clinical expertise, critical thinking, and decision-making abilities. Doctors must possess a thorough understanding of human anatomy, physiology, pathology, and pharmacology, as well as diagnostic and treatment modalities specific to their specialty area. Strong communication skills are essential for interacting with patients, colleagues, and interdisciplinary healthcare teams, as well as conveying complex medical information in a clear and empathetic manner. Additionally, doctors must demonstrate professionalism, integrity, and ethical conduct in their interactions with patients and adherence to medical standards of practice. The path to becoming a doctor typically involves completing a bachelor degree, followed by medical school and residency training in a chosen specialty. Medical school admissions are highly competitive, requiring strong academic performance, extracurricular activities, and standardized test scores (e.g., MCAT in the United States). After completing medical school, doctors must obtain a medical license through passing national licensing exams (e.g., USMLE in the United States) and fulfilling state-specific requirements. Subspecialty training, board certification, and continuing medical education may be pursued for career advancement and specialization.</string>
    <string name="salaryDoctor">In terms of salary, doctors earnings vary based on factors such as specialty, experience, geographical location, and practice setting. According to data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS), the median annual wage for physicians and surgeons was $208,000 in May 2020. However, salaries can range significantly higher for certain specialties such as orthopedic surgery, cardiology, and dermatology, while primary care specialties may have lower median salaries. Additionally, factors such as employment status (e.g., employed vs. self-employed), practice ownership, and geographic location can impact earning potential. Overall, doctors salaries reflect their extensive education, expertise, and responsibilities in providing medical care, promoting health, and improving patient outcomes.</string>

    <string name="jobLawyer">Lawyers have a range of job opportunities in various sectors, including law firms, government agencies, corporations, nonprofit organizations, and academia. The demand for lawyers is influenced by factors such as economic conditions, changes in legislation, and societal trends. While job prospects can be competitive, lawyers with specialized expertise or experience in high-demand areas may have favorable employment opportunities.</string>
    <string name="skillsLawyer">Lawyers require a combination of analytical, communication, research, and advocacy skills to excel in their profession. Analytical skills enable lawyers to analyze complex legal issues, identify relevant laws and precedents, and develop effective legal strategies. Strong communication skills are essential for articulating legal arguments, negotiating settlements, and interacting with clients, judges, and other legal professionals. Research skills are necessary for conducting legal research, gathering evidence, and preparing legal documents such as briefs, contracts, and pleadings. Advocacy skills are important for representing clients in court, presenting arguments persuasively, and advocating for their interests. To become a lawyer, individuals typically need to complete a bachelors degree, followed by a Juris Doctor (JD) degree from an accredited law school. Admission to law school is competitive and may require a high undergraduate GPA, a strong LSAT score, and letters of recommendation. After completing law school, aspiring lawyers must pass the bar exam in the state where they intend to practice and meet other state-specific licensing requirements, which may include character and fitness evaluations. Specialization through additional education, training, or certification may be pursued for career advancement in specific areas of law.</string>
    <string name="salaryLawyer">Overall, lawyers salaries reflect their education, expertise, and experience in providing legal advice, representation, and advocacy on behalf of clients. While the legal profession offers potential for lucrative earnings and career advancement, it also requires dedication, hard work, and ongoing professional development to succeed in a competitive and complex field.</string>
    <string name="counsellorAbout1">The counsellor holds a Ph.D. in Career Counseling and brings years of experience to her practice. With a keen understanding of the complexities of career decision-making, Dr. Patel specializes in guiding students and young professionals through educational and career planning processes. Her approach focuses on empowering individuals to explore their interests, values, and strengths to make informed choices that align with their personal and professional aspirations. Whether it\'s navigating college majors, exploring career options, or planning for graduate school, Dr. Patel offers personalized counseling sessions and comprehensive assessments to support her clients on their journey towards academic success and personal fulfillment.</string>

    <string name="resumeTips">1) Ensure your resume has a clean and professional format.\n 2) Keep your resume concise, ideally one page for entry-level positions.\n 3) Tailor your resume to the specific job you are applying for. \n 4) Include relevant keywords from the job description to pass ATS scans. \n 5) Regularly update your resume with new skills and experiences. \n 6) Maintain consistency in font styles, sizes, and formatting throughout. \n 7) List your key skills and technologies, focusing on those relevant to the job.\n 8) Proofread your resume carefully to avoid spelling and grammatical errors.</string>

    <string name="interviewTips">1) Research the company thoroughly, including its mission, values, products/services, and recent news.\n 2) Understand the job description and requirements to align your skills and experiences with the role.\n 3) Practice common interview questions and responses to articulate your experiences and accomplishments confidently. \n 4) Pay attention to your body language, maintain eye contact, and practice good posture to convey confidence and professionalism. \n 5) Dress appropriately for the interview, opting for professional attire that aligns with the company culture. \n 6) Prepare thoughtful questions to ask the interviewer about the company, role, team dynamics, and future opportunities. \n 7) Mentally prepare for the interview by visualizing success, managing stress, and maintaining a positive mindset.\n 8) Plan to arrive early for the interview to allow time for unexpected delays and to demonstrate punctuality and reliability.</string>

    <string name="jobSearchTips">1) Research potential employers and industries to target your job search effectively.\n 2) Leverage your professional network, including connections on LinkedIn, to uncover hidden job opportunities.\n 3) Customize your resume and cover letter for each job application to highlight relevant skills and experiences. \n 4) Utilize online job search platforms like Indeed, LinkedIn, and Glassdoor to explore job listings and company profiles. \n 5) Attend job fairs, career expos, and networking events to meet recruiters and learn about job openings. \n 6) Conduct informational interviews with professionals in your desired field to gain insights and expand your network. \n 7) Follow up with employers after interviews or networking events to express gratitude and reaffirm your interest in the position.\n 8) Continue to develop your skills and knowledge through online courses, workshops, and certifications to enhance your marketability.</string>





</resources>